Based On The Impossible True Story
Breakthrough is a drama film directed by Roxann Dawson.
Tragedy strikes when a woman named Joyce's son falls through the ice on a
frozen lake and is trapped underwater for over 15 minutes.
After being rushed to the hospital, the 14-year-old boy continues to fight for his life as
Joyce, her husband and their pastor stay by his bedside and pray for a miracle.
Joyce Smith, played by Chrissy Metz.
Brian Smith, played by Josh Lucas.
Pastor Jason Noble, played by Topher Grace.
Tommy Shine, played by Mike Colter.
John Smith, played by Marcel Ruiz.
Dr. Kent Sutterer, played by Sam Trammell.
Breakthrough is a 2019 American Christian drama film directed by
Roxann Dawson in her feature film directorial debut.
The film was written by Grant Nieporte, based on the Christian book The Impossible,
an account of true events written by Joyce Smith with Ginger Kolbaba.
It stars Chrissy Metz, Josh Lucas, Topher Grace, Mike
Colter, Marcel Ruiz and Dennis Haysbert.
Stephen Curry and Samuel Rodriguez are executive producers.
The film tells the story of a St.
Louis teenager who slipped through an icy lake on January 19, 2015, and was
underwater for 15 minutes before resuscitative efforts were started.
Although he was rescued, he remains in a coma, and his family
must rely on their faith to get through the ordeal.
Breakthrough premiered in St.
Louis on March 20, 2019, and was released in the United States on April 17, 2019, by 20th Century Fox,
as the studio's first feature film after the acquisition of 21st Century Fox by Disney.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the performances
and inspirational messages, but called the plot predictable.
The film garnered a nomination at the 92nd
Academy Awards for Best Original Song.
The film explores themes of coma, based on novel or book,
miracle, based on true story, family drama.
The tone is emotional.